Guide to the Stanley Legum experimental linguistics collection, 1960s-1970s
George Mason University Libraries
  - Snow and Legum, Syntactic Correlates of Composition Quality (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Wolfram, On What basis Variable Rules (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Winograd, Five Lectures on Artificial Intelligence (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Wolfram and Whiteman, The Role of Dialect Interference in Composition (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Williams, The Bitch Test: Black Intelligence Test of Cultural homogeneity (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Williams, Tell Martha Not to Moan (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Williams, Polyanova: A General Purpose Fortran IV Prog./Trend Analysis w/Equal-Unequal Space Levels-Variables (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Wilcox, A Note on the Length and Passing Score of a Mastery test (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Where Failure Make the Grade: Two Schools for Dropouts (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Western. Aug. Some Remarks on the Use of English Adverbs, 1906 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    Englischen Stuien 36
  - Weinreich, et. Al. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Watson, The Discovery of X-Rays (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Soulfood Chitlings test (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Wason, the Contexts of Plausible Denial (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Washington Dialect Study Questionnaire, Part I Elicitation of Narrative (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Wall and Rosembaum, The Auxiliary As A Muddy Turtle of If One Verb Won't Do it, Will three more (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Wall, Selectional Restrictions on Subjects and Transitive Verbs (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Thompson, On Subjectless Gerunds in English (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Thompson, The Underlying Structure of Relative Clauses (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Thompson, On the Notion 'Subjoined Clause' (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Thompson, Instead of and Rather Than Clause in English (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Thompson, Relative Clause Structures and Constraint on type of complex sentences (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Thompson, Handout for Seminar (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Thompson, Instructions (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Thompson, Semantic Theory of adverbs (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Thompson, et. Al., Who is 'Daddy'? (Revisited). The Status of Two-Year-Old's over-Extended (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Thomason and Stalnaker, A Semantic Theory of Adverbs (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Thomason, Species, Determinate and Natural Kinds (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Thomason, Some extension of Montague Grammar (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Stolz and Bills, Investigation of Standard-Nonstandard (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Stanford University Child Language Research From (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Stalnaker, Pragmatics (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Stalnakers, Pragmatic pre-suppositions (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Solan and Roeper, Children's Use of Syntactic Structure in Interpreting Relative Clause (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Wirth, Derivation of Cleft Sentences in English (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Wisdom, et. Al., Symposium: Other Minds (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Wise, The Taming of NIE; A Personal View (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Wolck and Matthews, A preliminary classification of adverbs in English (IU), August 1965 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Wolfram, Black-White Speech Differences Revisited (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Wolfram, Ibid. (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Wolfram, Sociolinguistic alternatives in teaching reading to non-standard speaker (2 files) (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Wolfram and Fasold, A Black English Translation of John 3: 1-21 With Grammatical Annotations, 1969 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - V. Wolfram, A Sociolinguistic Description of Detroit Negro Speech, November 1969 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Yeager and Benjamin, A List of Noun Homographs in English (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Young and Cliff, Interactive Scaling with Individual Subjects (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Young, Conjoint Scaling (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Young, A Fortran IV Program for Nonmetric Multidimensional Scaling (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Young, Nonmetric Multidimensional Scaling: Recovery of Metric Information (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Young, Nonmetric Scaling of Line lengths using Latencies, Similarity, and Same-Different judgments (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Young, Polynomial Conjoint Analysis: Some Second-Order Partial Derivatives (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Zubin, Experimental Validation of a Linguistic Analysis (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Zwicky, Auxiliary Reduction in English (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Henrie, A study of Verb Phrases Used by Five Year Old Nonstandard Negro English Speaking Children, June 1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Berkeley
  - Redden, Department of Linguistics, Occasional Papers on Linguistics, Number 1: Proceedings of the First International Conference on Frontiers in Language proficiency and Dominance Testing, Held at Southern Illinois University at Carbondale, April 21-23, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Horn, On the Semantic Properties of Logical Operators in English, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    A Dissertation, University of California
  - Foundation of Language, Volume 5, No. 2, May 1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Houston, Child Black English in Northern Florida: A sociolinguistic Examination, September 1969 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Monograph No. 3
  - Jackendoff, Some Rules of Semantic Interpretation For English, June 1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Chapters 1, 2, 3, Massachusetts
  - Partee, Negation, Conjunction, And Quantifiers: Syntax VS. Semantics, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Foundation of Language 6, 153 - 165
  - Hart, et. Al. Your Children's Language: A Key to Child Literacy (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Finm, Multivariance, Univariate and Multivariate Analysis of Variance, Covariance, and Regress, June 1968 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    New York, Version 4
  - A Preliminary Bibliography of American English Dialects, November 1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Emonds, Root and Structure-Preserving Transformations, June 1970 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Indiana University
  - Gleitman, Compound Nouns and English Speakers, November 10, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Philadelphia
  - Duncan, Report: Dominguez Hills Dialect Studies, October 1970 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    California State College
  - Confer, Linguistic Variability in a Philadelphia Speech Community, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Carroll, Development of Native Language Skills Beyond the Early Years, June 1968 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    Princeton
  - Carden, Logical Predicates and Idiolect Variation in English, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    Cambridge
  - Bills, On Case in Quechua, May 1969 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    Dissertation, Texas
  - Becker, Generative Phonology and Dialect Study: An Investigation of Three Modern German Dialects, August 1967 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Texas
  - Brown and Hanlon, Derivational Complexity and Order of Acquisition in Child Speech, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    Harvard University
  - Berdiansky, et. Al., Design for Sequencing Spelling-to-Sound Correspondences in Mod 2 Reading Program, June 4, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    Volume II
  - Berdiansky, Ibid (Box 13, Folder 18)
    Volume I
  - Aarons, et. Al. Linguistic-Cultural Differences and American Education, Spring/Summer 1969 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    The Florida FL Reporter: A Language Education Journal, Vol. 7, No. 1
  - Ferguson, Baby Talk in Sin Language (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Fischer, Syntax and Social Structure: Truk and Ponape (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Gumperz, On the Ethnology of Linguistic Change (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Hymes, two Types of Linguistic Relativity: Some Examples from American Ethnology (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Malkiel, Some Diachronic Implications of Fluid Speech Communities (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Samarin, Self-Annulling Prestige Factors Among Speakers of a Creole Language (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Labov, et. Al., A study of the Non-Standard English of Negro and Puerto Rican Speakers of New York City, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    Columbia University, Volume 1
  - Browning, Contrastive Collacational Analysis: Examples from Hindi and English, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    Dissertation, Austin
  - Huang, A study of Adverbs, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Dissertation, Ohio
  - Jonas, Translation of programming Languages, June 1968 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Joos, Readings in Linguistics: The Development of descriptive Linguistics in America since 1925, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    New York
  - Kennedy, Children's Comprehension of Natural Language, November 1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Labov, et. Al. Vol.1, pp. 95-245, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Labov, Ibid, Vol. 1, pp. 246-375 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Labov, Ibid, Vol. 2, pp. 196-end (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Labov, Ibid, Vol. 2, p. 195 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Lakoff, On the Nature of Syntactic Irregularity, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    Harvard
  - McCoard, The Methods of Dialectology, March 27, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Penn, Linguistic Relativity Versus Innate Ideas: the Origins of the Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis in German Though of the Eighteenth and Nineteenth Centuries, June 1966 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Nida, Morphology: The Descriptive Analysis of Words, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Michigan
  - Pike, Phonemics: A Technique for Reducing Languages to Writing, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Pittman and Kerr, Papers on the Language of the Australian Aborigines, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Canberra
  - Rand, The Syntax of Chinese Interrogative Structures, April 16, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Ross, Constraints on Variables in Syntax, September 1967 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    Yale
  - Stolz and Bills, Child Development Evaluation and Research Center, August 1968 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - UCLA Conference, On Historical Linguistics, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - UCLA Conference, On Historical Linguistics (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - LSA Meeting, Winter 1970 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - L.S.A. Meeting, Summer meeting (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - LSA Meeting, December 1969 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - American Education Research: Association Conference, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Performadilla Conference (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Program and Notes by S. Legum
  - Rudegeair, technical Report No. 146: The Effect of Contextual Influence on Children's Discrimination of initial Consonants, September 1970 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Wisconsin
  - Rudegeair and Kamil, Technical Report No. 118: Assessment of Phonological Discrimination in Children, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Stechnow, Linguistische Berichte 13, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Germany
  - Lehiste, et. Al. Working Papers in Linguistics No. 12, June 1972 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Ohio
  - Research Foundation: Project on Linguistic Analysis Report No. II, June 1965 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Ohio State University
  - Research Foundation: Working Papers in Linguistics, December 1976 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Herbert, Proceedings of the Sixth Conference On African Linguistics, April 12-13, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Herbert, Patterns in Language, Culture, And Sub-Saharan Africa, April 11, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Garvey and Baldwin, Studies in Convergent Communication: III Comparisons of Child and Adult Performance, February 1971 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    The John Hopkins University, Report No. 94
  - Garvey and Baldwin, Studies in Convergent Communication: I Analysis of Verbal Interaction, February 1970 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    The John Hopkins University, Report No. 88
  - Garvey and Baldwin, Studies in Convergent Communication: II A measure of Communication Accuracy, February 1970 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    The John Hopkins University, Report No. 71
  - Garvey and Baldwin, A Self-Instructional Program in Standard English: development and Evaluation, September 1969 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Guthrie, Feedback and Sentence Learning, June 1970 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Grosu, The Strategic Content of Island Constraints: Working Papers in Linguistics No. 13, December 1972 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Geis, et. Al., Mostly Syntax and Semantics: Working Papers in Linguistics No. 16, December 1973 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Gendel, et. Al., Working Papers in Linguistics No. 18, June 1975 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Fillmoe, Working Papers in Linguistics No. 10, August 1971 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Garnica, Papers in Psycholinguistics, Working Papers in Linguistics No. 22, February 1977 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Garnes et. Al. Working Papers in Linguistics No. 17, May 1974 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Drachman, et. Al. Working Papers in Linguistics No. 15, April 1873 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Fillmore, Indirect Object Constructions in English and the Ordering of Transformation, February 1962 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Fillmore, et. Al., The Position of Embedding Transformations in a Grammar, March 1963 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Fillmore, et. Al., Project On Linguistic Analysis Report no. 13, August 1966 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Schachter and Bedell, Critiques of Syntactic Studies II, March 1973 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Bedell, Studies In East Asian Syntax, October 1972 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Bedell, Exploration in Syntactic Theory, July 1972 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Niedermeyer, Prototype Testing in Instructional Development, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    SWRL Working Papers, California
  - McManus, Design of an Instructional Management System, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Follettie and Teplitzky, Computer-Based Systems to Facilitate Instructional Development, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Bessemer and Smith, The Integration of Content, Task and Skills Analysis Techniques in Instructional Design, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Jensen, How Much can We Boost IQ and Scholastic Achievement, Winter 1969 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Harvard Educational Review Vol. 39 No. 1
  - Follettie, Achievement Information Monitoring in Schools (AIM) (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Larger Straws, SWRL Educational Research and Development, May 1, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Professional Papers 36
  - Garcia, et. Al., Research in the Black Community: A Need For Self-Determination, October 1969 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    SWRL, SR10 30
  - Follettie, Semiautomation of Instructional Status Information (ISI): Characteristics of a School-Sited Electronic System (SSE), April 21, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    SERL
  - Tosti, Domestic Crisis Intervention: A Text for Law Enforcement Officers (Box 16, Folder 10)
    NCED, San Franciso
  - Thompson, On Relative Clause Structures in Relation to the Nature of Sentence Complexity, Fall, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Shuy, et. Al., Sociolinguistic Theory, Materials and Training Programs: Three Related Studies, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Washington D.C.
  - Shuy, et. Al., Linguistic Correlates of Social Stratification in Detroit, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Cooperative Research Project No. 6-1347, Michigan
  - Sheldon, The Acquisition of Relative Clauses in English, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Symposium on Multilingualism: Second Meeting of the Inter-African Committee On Linguistic, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    Brazzaville
  - Rosenbaum, Language Universals and Zapotec Syntax, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Robson, On the Generation of Passive Constructions in English, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Pfaff, A Sociolinguistic Study of Black Children in Los Angeles, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Perlmutter, deep and Surface Structure Constraints in Syntax, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - West, Bilingualism (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Ch. 7 - end (pp. 202-354)
  - West, Bilingualism (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Through - Ch. VI (pp. 1-201)
  - Pope, Questions and Answers In English, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Torrey, The Language of Black Children in the Early Grades, February 1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Williams, et. Al. Attitudinal Correlates of Children's Speech Characteristics, March 1971 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Williams, Quechua Phonology, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Wolfram, Social Dialects From a Linguistic Perspective: Assumptions, Current Research, and Future Directions, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Wolfram and Fasold, Overlapping Influence in the English of Second Generation Puerto Rican Teenagers in Harlem, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Washington D.C. pp. 1-178
  - Wolfram and Fasold, Ibid (Box 17, Folder 10)
    pp. 179-355
  - Wolfram and Fasol, Ibid (Box 17, Folder 11)
    pp. 356-452
  - Wolfram and Christian, Sociolinguistic Variables in Appalachian Dialects, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Virginia
  - Linguistic Analysis, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    New York, Volume 1. No. 1
  - AERA Annual meeting Program, April 13-17, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Los Angeles
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America, Forty Second Annual meeting, December 28-30, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Chicago, Illinois
  - Newsletter of the American Dialect Society, February and June 1974 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Volume 6 No. 1 and No. 2
  - Newsletter of the American Dialect Society, November 1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Volume 6 No. 3
  - Newsletter of the American Dialect Society, June 1976 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Volume 8 No. 2
  - Passow, Secondary Reform: Retrospect and Prospect, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Columbia University
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America: Forty Eighth Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    San Diego, California
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America: Fifty First Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
  - Clark, Marietta, Ohio: The Continuing Erosion of a Speech Island, 26390 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Publication of the American Dialect Society, Number 57
  - Foley, A Phonological and Lexical Study of the Speech of Tuscaloosa County, Alabama, November 1972 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Publication of the American Dialect Society, Number 56
  - Preston, Bituminous Coal Mining Vocabulary of the Eastern United States, April 1973 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    Publication of the American Dialect Society, Number 59
  - Newsletter of the International Computer Archie of Modern English (ICAME), November 1981 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Oslo, No. 5
  - Regional Language Studies, January 15, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Newfoundland, No. 3
  - Dijik and Petofi, Text: an Interdisciplinary Journal for the study of Discourse, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    Volume 1-1
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America, Fortieth Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America, Forty Third Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    New York, New York
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America, Forty Fourth Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    San Francisco, California
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America, Forty Fifth Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America, Forty Sixth Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    St. Louis, Missouri
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America, Forty Ninth Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America, Fiftieth Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Meeting Handbook, Linguistic Society of America, Fifty Second Annual Meeting, December 28-30, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Program of the 69th Annual Meeting: American Anthropological Association, November 19-22, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Annual Meeting Program, American Educational Research Association, February 25 - March 1, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    New Orleans, Louisiana